Finding Aid for the Pat And Lily Okura Papers LSC.2367
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 8: Personal record files, 1912-2009
  - Commendations, 1980 May 31 (Box 225, Folder 1)
    This contains a County of Los Angeles commendation to K. Patrick Okura by Edmund D. Edelman, Supervisor, Third District. It was presented after an UCLA Alumni Association event on May 31, 1980, at a community event sponsored by Special Services for Groups and Friends of Pat Okura.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 31 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    This contains a plaque presented by Asian American Drug Abuse Program (AADAP).
  - Commendations, 1980 May 31 (Box 198, Folder 4)
    This contains a plaque presented by Asian American Social Workers (AASW).
  - Commendations, 1999 October 14 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    This contains materials on the 25th Anniversary Gala of the AA Community Mental Health Services.
  - Commendations, 1999 December 13 (Box 161, Folder 7-9)
    This contains materials on Japan's Order of the Rising Sun and Gold Rays with Rosette from the Embassy of Japan in Washington, D.C. One folder contains photographs.
  - Commendations, 1999 December 13 (Box 229, Folder 1)
    This folder contains medallion and commendation with translation on Japan's Order of the Rising Sun and Gold Rays with Rosette for framed presentation by the Embassy of Japan in Washington, D.C.
  - Commendations, 2001 June 24 (Box 161, Folder 10)
    This contains the Honorary Doctor of Letters awarded by Phillips Graduate Institute.
  - Commendations, 2005 May 24 (Box 161, Folder 11-12)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
    This contains an American Psychiatric Association Committee of AA Psychiatrists Kun-Po Soo Award posthumously awarded to K. Patrick Okura. Folder 12 contains a two-disc CD of a presentation on the life of Patrick Okura by Russell F. Lim.
  - Commendations, 2005 May 24 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    This contains an American Psychiatric Association Committee of AA Psychiatrists Kun-Po Soo Award.
  - Okura wedding and anniversaries, 1941-1991 (Box 161, Folder 13-15)
  - Okura wedding and anniversaries, 1941 (Box 186, Folder 12)
    This contains the bride's scrapbook album.
  - Okura wedding and anniversaries, 1991 (Box 162, Folder 1-2)
    This contains a photograph album and program material of the 50th wedding anniversary. Folder 1 contains 35mm slides.
  - Okura wedding and anniversaries, 2001 October (Box 162, Folder 3-4)
    This contains materials on the 60th wedding anniversary and K. Patrick Okura's 90th birthday. Also contains a photograph album.
  - K. Patrick Okura birthdays, 1988-1999 (Box 162, Folder 5-7)
    This contains an 88th birthday photograph album.
  - K. Patrick and Lily Okura vitae and professional records, 1934-2001 (Box 163, Folder 1-6)
    This contains K. Patrick Okura's curriculum vitae.
  - K. Patrick Okura published works, 1973-2000 (Box 163, Folder 7-11)
    This contains a manuscript of A Brief History of the Center for Minority Group Mental Health Programs at the NIMH by Bertram S. Brown and K. Patrick Okura published in Mental Health, Racism, and Sexism, edited by Charles V. Willie, et al.
  - K. Patrick Okura unpublished works, 1962-1974 (Box 163, Folder 12-14)
    Folder 12 contains correspondence regarding published and unpublished works, and microfiche copies of two unpublished works submitted to the Educational Resources Information Center (ERIC).
  - K. Patrick Okura unpublished works, 1975-2001 (Box 164, Folder 1-8)
  - K. Patrick Okura UCLA diplomas, 1933 and 1935 (Box 224, Folder 3)
- Series 9: Correspondence files, 1932-2005
  The Correspondence files contain general correspondence, answered correspondence, and James Galvin correspondence.
  - General Correspondence, 1932-1940 (Box 165, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 165, Folder 6-12)
  - General Correspondence, 1941-1948 (Box 166, Folder 1-6)
  - General Correspondence, 1949-1969 (Box 166, Folder 7-8)
  - General Correspondence, 1969-1981 (Box 167, Folder 1-6)
  - General Correspondence, 1970-1981 (Box 168, Folder 1-4)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 168, Folder 5-7)
  - General Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 1-4)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-2000 (Box 169, Folder 5-7)
  - General Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 170, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 171, Folder 1-6)
  - General Correspondence, 1983-2005 (Box 172, Folder 1-4)
  - Answered Correspondence, 1940-1943 (Box 172, Folder 5-7)
  - Answered Correspondence, 1943 (Box 173, Folder 1-3)
  - Answered Correspondence, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 4-5)
  - James Galvin Correspondence, 1946-1970 (Box 173, Folder 6)
- Series 10: Resource files, 1915-2004
  The Resource files contain subject files, publications, and photograph albums.
  Arrangement
  Folders are arranged by subject in alphabetical order, books are arranged by subject after subject folder in title order.
  - Subject File--Aging and the elderly, 1980-1986 (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Depression in the elderly: a behavioral treatment manual, by Dolores Gallagher and Larry W. Thompson, 1981 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    This contains a book.
  - Minority aging: essential curricula content for selected health and allied health professions, by US Department of Health and Human Services, 1990 (Box 174, Folder 3)
  - Subject File--AIDS and HIV prevention, 1987-1993 (Box 174, Folder 4)
  - Subject File--Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders (AAPI), 1985-1999 (Box 174, Folder 5-7)
  - The Asian Americans: Changing Patterns, Changing Needs by Bok-Lim C. Kim, 1978 (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Asian Americans in transition, by Stanley Karnow and Nancy Yoshihara, 1992 (Box 175, Folder 2)
  - Congressional pictorial directory: ninety-seventh Congress of the United States, 1981 (Box 175, Folder 3)
  - Official congressional directory: 97th Congress, 1981 (Box 175, Folder 4)
  - Yell-oh girls!: emerging voices explore culture, identity, and growing up Asian American, by Vickie Nam, 2001 (Box 175, Folder 5)
  - Subject File--Census and demographic reports, 1985-1997 (Box 176, Folder 1-2)
  - Subject File--Civil rights, 1963-1996 (Box 176, Folder 3)
  - The Administration of Injustice by Melvin P. Sikes, 1975 (Box 176, Folder 4)
  - Discriminatory Employment of Asian Americans: Private Industry in the San Francisco-Oakland SMSA by Amado Y. Cabezas and Harold T. Yee, 1977 July 4 (Box 176, Folder 5)
  - Race relations, by Harry H. L. Kitano, 1974 (Box 176, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights Issues Facing Asian Americans in the 1990s: A Report of the United States Commission on Civil Rights, 1992 Feb (Box 176, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights Digest, U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1967-1997 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Civil Rights Update, newsletter of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1991-1997 (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - Subject File--Cultural competence and diversity, 1971-2001 (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Subject File--East Asian mental health, 1969-1985 (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - Subject File--Families, 1975-1995 (Box 177, Folder 5)
  - Subject File--Filipino Americans, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 6)
  - Makibaka: the Pilipino American struggle, by Royal F. Morales, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 7)
  - Subject File--Health, 1978 (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - The Soul of the Surgeon, by Rudolph Matas, 1915 (Box 177, Folder 9)
  - Subject File--Indochinese refugees, 1979-2003 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Evaluating victim services, edited by Susan E. Salasin, 1981 (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - Subject File--Japanese Americans, 1986-2000 (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - The anatomy of dependence, by Takei Doi, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 4)
  - Generations and identity: the Japanese Americans, by Harry H. L. Kitano, 1993 (Box 178, Folder 5)
  - The Issei: the world of the first generation Japanese immigrants, 1885-1924, by Yuji Ichioka, 1988 (Box 178, Folder 6)
  - Directory of Japanese students in North America and Hawaii, 1927-1928, by the Japanese Students' Christian Association in North America (Box 178, Folder 7)
  - Subject File--Japanese Americans and World War II, 1966-1991 (Box 178, Folder 8)
  - Subject File--Japanese Americans and World War II, 1944-1992 (Box 179, Folder 1-2)
  - Achieving the impossible dream: how Japanese Americans obtained redress, by Mitchell Maki, Harry H.L. Kitano, and S. Megan Berthold, 1999 (Box 179, Folder 3)
  - Americans: story of the 442nd Combat Team, by Orville C. Shirey, 1946 (Box 179, Folder 4)
  - And justice for all: an oral history of the Japanese American detention camps, by John Tateishi, 1984 (Box 179, Folder 5)
  - Letters from the front: Boys Town on the battlefield from Pearl Harbor to the Persian Gulf, by Terry L. Hyland and Hugh J. Reilly, 1995 (Box 179, Folder 6)
  - Lone Heart Mountain, by Estelle Ishigo, 1972 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - People in motion: the postwar adjustment of the evacuated Japanese Americans, by the War Agency Liquidation Unit formerly War Relocation Authority, of the US Department of the Interior, 1947 (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Prejudice, war and the Constitution, by Jacobus tenBroek, Edward N. Barnhart, and Floyd W. Matson, 1968 (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Righting a wrong: Japanese Americans and the passage of the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, by Leslie T. Hatamiya, 1993 (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - Secret embedded in Magic cables: the story of a 101 year old Japanese communist leader who served Japan, by James Oda, 1993 (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - This is my own: letters to Wes and other writings on Japanese Canadians, 1941-1948, by Muriel Kitagawa and Roy Miki, 1985 (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Subject File--Mental health, Community, 1965-1992 (Box 181, Folder 1-2)
  - Subject File--Mental health, Minority, 1976-1978 (Box 181, Folder 3-4)
  - Racism and mental health: essays. Contemporary Community Health Series, edited by Charles V. Willie, Bernard M. Kramer, and Bertram S. Brown, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Who's who in National Institute of Mental Health (4th ed), by US Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1971 October (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Subject File--Substance abuse, 1989-1990 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Cultural competence for evaluators: a guide for alcohol and other drug abuse prevention practitioners working with ethnic/racial communities, edited by Mario A. Orlandi for the US Department of Health and Human Services, 1992 (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Subject File--Vietnamese/Southeast Asian Americans, 1989 (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Southeast Asian mental health, edited by Tom Choken Owan for US Department of Health and Human Services with Office of Refugee Resettlement, 1985 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Subject File--Women, 1976 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Subject File--Youth, 1982-1998 (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Photograph Albums Index lists compiled by Lily Okura, 1982-1998 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Photograph Albums, 1982-1989 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1989-1992 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1990-1993 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1992-1995 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1995-1996 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1996 (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1996-1997 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1997-1998 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1998 (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 1999 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 2001-2002 (Box 214, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Albums, 2002-2004 (Box 215, Folder 1)